Francisco Oliveira

IT Department & Software Engineering

E-mail franciscooliveira.it@gmail.com

WWW www.franciscooliveira.ml

Self-motivated Developer adds high level of experience collaborating and working on multiple web-based projects. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability, and security. Organized approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines. Pulls from active knowledge of current technology landscape to promote best practices in web design.

Skills

■■■■ Excellent	Product Development	
■■■□ Very Good	Hardware and Software Installation	
■■■□ Very Good	Technical Analysis	
■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent	Programming	
■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent	Software Development	
■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent	Technical Support	
■■■□ Very Good	JavaScript Experience	
■■■□ Very Good	Project Management	
■■■■ Excellent	Skilled in Using Python	
■■■■ Excellent	Innovative	
■■■□ Very Good	Operational Leadership	
■■■□ Very Good	Corporate Leadership	
■■■■ Excellent	Web Development Experience	

Education

2019-09 - Current

High School Diploma

High School

Certifications

Python Core

WebDev - HTML/CSS/JS

Information Technology

Work History

2021-08 - Current

Developer & Manager

LushNodes

- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.

2021-08 - Current

System Operator & Technical Support Officer

Wyvern Hosting

- Suggested specific ideas for process, productivity, and safety improvements.
- Analysed and inspected operating units such as towers, storage tanks and other units to check operation and improve efficiency.
- Analysed and developed service goals for in-bound call centre.
- Increased customer satisfaction ratings

2021-07 - Current

Freelance Developer

CyberFlair

- Developed programs from ground up using measured, market-focused approach to eliminate waste and streamline implementation cycle.
- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.

2021-07 - Current

Development Manager

Atlas Co.

- Resolved problems, improved operations, and provided exceptional service.
- Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Eliminated downtime and maximized revenue by providing top project quality control.

2021-05 - Current

Freelance Developer

World of Discord

- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.
- Developed programs from ground up using measured, market-focused approach to eliminate waste and streamline implementation cycle.

2021-07 - 2021-09

Managing Director

Aztec Gaming

- Assessed performance management structures and implemented enhancements to improve frameworks and strengthen results.
- Spearheaded successful business development initiatives aligned with company's strategy and core competencies.

Focused teams on developing innovative and cutting-edge approaches at all levels with effective resource allocation and strategic planning.

2021-05 - 2021-08

CTO

Vee Inc.

- Managed company-level architecture, platform and data configuration processes and implementation protocols.
- Laid out complete business continuity plan to maintain data protection in event of natural disaster or long-term outage.

2021-01 - 2021-07

CEO

Adapt Development

- Coached and guided senior managers to improve effectiveness and policy enforcement, resulting in improved employee job satisfaction and higher performance levels.
- Improved business profits through strategic updates to processes, procedures, and team makeup.

Software

sonware		
	Python	■ ■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
	HTML/CSS	■ ■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
	JavaScript	■■■□ Very Good
	SQL	■ ■ □ □ □ Good
	Office	■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
	VS Code	■ ■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
Languages		
	English	■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
	Portuguese	■ ■ ■ ■ Excellent
	German	■ □ □ □ □ Basic
Interests		
	Play Music	
	Compose & Produce Music	
	Code	

Design